We're going to build an AEO / SEO
strategy for this e-commerce website.
So, the first thing you want to do when
you're really starting to think about
how you're going to attack an e-commerce
campaign is you don't want to try to go
after the entire website. It's one of
the biggest mistakes. I've made this
mistake more times than I can count in
the early days of my SEO career and I
would try to basically rank everything,
go after every category. And what ends
up happening is you end up going like a
centimeter in each direction. And really
what you want to do is just pick one
category that you just want to
absolutely dominate. So, in this case,
I've already pre-selected one, which is
going to be creatine, okay? So, usually
what you can do is just go to the main
menu and identify a category. But in
this case, we're just going to go ahead
and pick one of these. So, let's go with
creatine, very popular supplement, and
we're going to try to focus in on just
this one category. Because what you're
going to realize when you do this,
there's so much work to do. There's so
much work to do in just one little
segment, one little cluster, that it
becomes nearly impossible to think about
anything else. So, what you really want
to think about is for this one little
category, you really what we're going to
do in this video is we're going to build
a 90-day plan, okay? So, basically a
quarter, so one entire quarter focus on
just trying to dominate this one topic,
all right? That's what we're trying to
do. So, what's the first step? So, the
step in the process is to pick the
category, which we've done already, so
we're good to go. So, the next step in
the process is to run a technical audit.
So, what that means is we're going to
crawl the website and we're going to
ultimately look at this website just
through the lens of that one category,
okay? We're not going to try to focus on
anything else, we're just going to focus
on that one category. So, normally when
you run a technical audit, what you
would have is you'd see scroll over here
and you would have access to Google
Search Console, which would give you all
this data. Then you would have access to
Google Analytics and you would even have
access to Bing Webmaster Tools. But in
this case, obviously So don't have
access to these tools for this
particular business. So but when you do
have access, this is what it would
normally look like. You scroll over here
and you can see all this beautiful data,
right? You've got all the impressions
and clicks and CTR and position. Then
you've got the Bing in there, too. So
now you've got two different dimensions
that you can look at. And then also
you've got Google Analytics 4 and of
course you see all that data as well. So
what that allows you to do is make
quantifiable decisions. We're not just
guessing. We're using the data to inform
us and make the right decisions. And so
this is really important when you do any
audit. You don't even need to use
Rankability. Just any audit that you're
going to do, you need to integrate these
data points. It's so critical because
when you start to assign actions to
these URLs, you need to be doing it
based on data, not based on your gut or
other things. Just follow the data and
let the data guide you, okay? But along
those lines, so what I'm going to do
here is just because I don't have access
to their data, I'm really doing this
just for one pure reason, which is to
measure their topic authority in
specifically that creatine cluster. So
I'm just going to download this CSV and
we're going to go ahead and freeze up
this row. And like I said, I'm not
interested in everything. I'm just
interested in the one specific cluster,
which is creatine. So the simplest thing
to do is just come right in here and
just do text contains and then just do
creatine. And then we'll be able to see
right away in a title tag what we're
working with, right? So I'm going to go
ahead and just hide these so we can see
it better. All right. So what I see here
is it looks like we've got about,
let's say, seven pages, give or take,
that are built around creatine. Now this
wasn't a full website crawl, so there
could be more. Now this crawl revealed
about seven pages or so. And typically
when you see this many pages, there's a
very high probability that many of these
pages do not have good signals. And so
this is why having the data is really
important because you may find that some
of these pages need to be maybe
consolidated or upgraded or in some
cases deleted if they're not very good,
okay? But if you want to do another
quick check just to see like a real a
quick assessment of topic coverage, just
go right into Google and this is the
simplest thing to do. You don't even
need any tool to do this. Just do First
Form or whatever the brand is you're
working on and then just put whatever
that core seed is for that topic, okay,
like this. And what I'll do is I'll just
go ahead and look at this and see, okay,
do they have a significant amount of
assets built around this core topic,
right? And you start to look at this and
it looks like they've hit it pretty
hard, right? They have pretty good topic
coverage here based on what I'm seeing.
So, it looks like they've covered it
pretty well on their blog. And okay, so
I would say let's call it like 30
assets, give or take, around creatine.
What you're going to find is like that
on the surface might seem like a lot,
but believe it or not that's actually
not that much. 30 around this topic is
actually very small. When you think
about the amount of assets you're going
to need to build true topic authority in
this one little segment, you're going to
need a couple hundred assets across
distributed across the blog, the
website, and across their owned assets
which I'll be talking about here in a
second, okay? So, running that technical
audit, we're good to go. And like I
said, we're not doing a full SEO audit
here. We're just doing it we just did
that brief technical audit just to
identify the cluster, okay? So, now we
did is we did the quick assessment, so
we got that. We're pretty much good on
there. All right, so now what we're
going to do is we want to focus on
what's going to be our content strategy
overall. Now, you know, they've got a
pretty good amount of pages built around
creatine, but even then we're still
going to build the build the strategy
from scratch because we have to be
organized to be able to do this the
right way. So, one thing you can do is
you can come in here and build a very
simple template, okay? And this is the
easiest way to go about thinking about
this is which is the five stages of
customer awareness. So, what that means
is right here, we've got basically five
stages that a potential prospect might
go through. And this doesn't mean they
go through this in in an hour or a whole
day. It could be years that takes them
to go through this whole funnel, right?
But now with AI, this can actually
happen very quickly, right? Someone can
go from completely unaware, which I'll
be showing here in a second, to all the
way down to the bottom of the funnel
where they're actually buying something,
okay? And so, this is really important.
But, what you want to think about here
is you want to attack topics at each
stage of this funnel. Now, what I like
to do is I like to do it in reverse, and
I like to start with the bottom of the
funnel, which is most aware. Most aware
means that these topics are directly
related to First Form's creatine, okay?
So, what you're looking at here, these
are a bunch of topics that are very
specific to the stuff that they sell,
okay? And all of these topics need to
either be covered on the actual creatine
pages themselves or splintered off into
a dedicated assets, right? It just
depends. Depending on the complex the
complexity of the topic, sometimes a
whole dedicated page is required. Other
times, it might just be good in a little
FAQ section. You just got to use your
best judgment on that front. But, the
question is how did I come up with these
ideas? I didn't magically come up with
these, okay? All I did is I went in here
and I put in their creatine page, their
collection page. And actually, if you
want to go to the next level on this, I
would also go in here and I would add
all of their product pages in here for
the specific cluster, okay? So, we're
going to go ahead and add Let's go ahead
and add a couple others in here. So,
I'll put this one in. We'll grab this
one. And what we're doing here is we're
feeding the AI a lot of information and
grounding, so it is working from a place
of reality, not from a place of just its
pure large language model base
knowledge. And that's we don't want it
to do that. We want it to be grounded,
but we want to leverage its
intelligence. That's the key. All right,
so now what we have here is we have five
sources all built around creatine, okay?
And what we can do is I'm actually going
to take the same exact one, the same
prompt that I used here, and we're going
to start a new conversation. And let's
just go ahead and run this again, okay?
And what you what it will do now is it's
going to look at all five of those
sources, and then it's going to
formulate a strategy based on those five
sources, which is exactly what we want,
right? So going back to the most aware
phase as I mentioned earlier, you can
see here I just used a very simple
prompt, right? So create Please create
topic ideas for the five stages of
customer awareness, and then so on and
so forth. I said the whole thing. And
then basically the AI went through and
built out these different ideas. Now, of
course, you don't just want to do these
blanket and just focus on them without
any human judgment, but it's a beginning
place to start, right? This is the base.
Some of these will be good, 20% of them
will be bad. Focus on the ones that are
actually worth attacking. Now, we'll go
back here, and this is going to be a
refinement of that original prompt that
I did, because now we've got five
sources. And we can see here that Okay,
so this is kind of cool, because what
happened here is it's showing basically
the strategy, but it's also now looking
at the grounding of performance. And you
can see here I already ran some of their
kind of core topics in our tracker, and
you can see that they're not doing too
well at this point, okay? And so what's
going to happen is the AI is not just
going to look at their strategy or look
at their brand, it's also going to look
at their performance and kind of kind of
try and bring those two things together,
because it's grounded based on the
performance and the data inside of the
platform, okay? So what you're going to
see here is it's talking about its
performance right now. So we'll go over
here, and by the way, this becomes even
more powerful when you have all the
integrations, right? So you got Google
Search Console in here integrated. What
it will do is it will then go look at
all the data related to creatine
specifically and bring that into the
intelligence and in and have more
grounding in that way. Okay, so it's
calling for making a creatine hub and
this actually does make a lot of sense
because we're going to be building out
once you build out the five stages
customer awareness correctly, that's
going to make a lot of sense to probably
build out a hub just because we're going
to have cover so many topics. This is
another one here talking about putting
more FAQs in and then owned asset uh
amplification which we'll be talking
about here as well. Okay, so this is
basically just to give you a nice little
base to work from and like I said, this
is really important and no matter what
you use, you don't have to use
Rankability. You could technically do
this in ChatGPT projects and put a bunch
of sources in there and then let it do
this kind of similar assessment. You
could do it in Claude, too. But it's a
lot better when you've got kind of
everything in one unit. So you've got
the data, you've got the knowledge base,
you've got the intelligence layer that
that's built into this platform that's
specifically built for SEO and AEO. It's
a very different thing altogether. But
with that in mind, we're going to go
back over here and so essentially what
you want to start with is building the
most aware phase. Now this is literally
40 different topics. What I would
normally do is I'd go into Google Search
Console and I would extract more stuff.
So I would filter by first form, I'd
filter by first form creatine and I
would find more opportunities there to
fill in this part of the funnel. So
start here. This is stuff where you can
win so easily and this is stuff that you
should be just be doing. Any brand
should be doing this, okay? This is your
greatest opportunity to get some quick
wins with basically no effort at all
because your competitors can't beat you
on these. Let's go over to the tracker
and basically I put in five different
topics, all with different intent. Okay,
these have different intents. So you can
see gummies specifically that's a little
bit broader and then they have gummies
for women. Now they don't sell gummies
as far as I know, but it's still
important to show that there's not a lot
of coverage in that one little area.
Another one here is monohydrate powder
versus monohydrate supplements. This
could you could argue this is a slight
variant and the AI will maybe
consolidate this together and treat it
the same, but just in general I do want
to see if there's any slight variance on
that. And then of course broadly best
creatine supplements, okay? So let's go
ahead and start with the ones where they
actually like this is what they sell.
Let's go broad here, which is best
creatine supplements. So what we're
looking at here is we're trying to see
what is their performance for this topic
across every search surface. So we go
into traditional search, let's go ahead
and take a look and they don't have
virtually any presence with their owned
domain, right? So their domain does not
appear for any of this, okay? So that's
already opportunity number one. Now
we're going to go over here to AI
answers. Do they get mentioned as one of
the top products? The answer is no,
okay? They're not showing up in here at
all and so this tells us that we need to
really improve on this, okay? And then
go to the AI citations. Are they used as
a core source of retrieval and do any of
these sources mention them, okay? So you
can actually just run this and basically
what this will do is it will crawl all
of the top citations and see if First
Form is actually appearing in these
specific pages. And it looks like they
do not appear basically in any of these.
This is really not good if you want to
perform well for this particular topic,
but if you want to show up when people
search anything related to what are the
best creatine supplements and every
variant of that, this is where the focus
has to be. You have to get visibility
here. Now there's so many ways to do
this. We'll talk about this in a second,
but this is the first step to fixing
this is identifying the opportunities in
the citations tab. It is so critical.
And then in video search is another
opportunity here where you can start to
see are we actually are we getting is
our brand getting mentioned on YouTube,
okay? This is another big one cuz
YouTube is a one of the top sources of
retrieval in AI platforms. Same thing in
TikTok. Okay, we're looking at TikTok
now and we can see are we getting
coverage for this topic on TikTok,
right? So, you want to tackle every
single search surface that you can. And
in this case, there's a ton of
opportunity here, like tons. And this is
the craziest thing about this, all
right? First Form is a massive brand,
okay? We'll go into first We'll just go
into Google, okay? First Form TikTok.
We'll see how many They've got 400,000
followers on TikTok. They've got Let's
go on Instagram. I bet they got at least
several hundreds of thousands. Oh, they
got a million followers on Instagram,
okay? A million. Let's go to their
YouTube. They've got 22 or 200,000
followers on on on YouTube. And then
when you combine the personal brands of
the founders of these companies and all
the people that they're working with,
they have just an enormous brand. So, it
is mind-blowing to me that with that,
they're still not doing well here, which
means that they haven't really gotten
focused in correctly. And this shows
that if you want to do well in search,
it's not just about having an enormous
brand and everything's going to take
care of itself. That's just not true
because you got to get really focused,
super focused in specific categories
like we're doing today, okay? So, first
thing I'm going to do here is I'm going
to go to here and I'm literally just
going to export Okay, then once you've
exported the traditional search results,
next best thing is actually to go over
here and export the competitors. Then go
to the AI citations tab and do the same
exact thing and just export these again.
So, then what you want to do is go
through this exact process for at least
five core queries that are really
important. Now, of course, this doesn't
cover everything and this would take
many hours to get this squared away, but
at least get the five core. And this is
important at the beginning of the
campaign. So, basically, what you want
to do is identify, let's say, five core
topics, export traditional search
results, export the competitors that are
appearing in the AI answers, and then
export the AI citations. And from there,
we're going to have a nice base to work
from. Because if you think about it,
we've got about 53 citations here across
all of these AI platforms. So, when you
multiply this by five, we're going to be
dealing with, let's say, 250, give or
take, citations, and then also the
traditional search results, which is
about 30 per report. So, what we're
trying to do is get a lay of the land
and identify every opportunity that we
can to ultimately attack these topics.
Once you've got a good knowledge base in
place, you can run a prompt like this.
So, give me 20 variants of insert your
keyword plus use case that all have
unique intent. And so, you can see here,
the AI went through and came up with a
bunch of unique use cases and different
types of intent. And this is really
important for when you're trying to
extract a lot of opportunities from AI.
You want to hit on those different types
of intent, okay? And so, what I did is I
took a few of these and ran them through
the tracker. So, now you can see here,
we've got all these different variants,
all these different types of intent
where we're going to want to try to
dominate for as many of these as
possible in this one segment or this one
category. And you can see which is
honestly, it's pretty amazing that a
brand of this magnitude is really not
showing up basically for anything. And
so, what I did is I went ahead and I
exported basically [clears throat] the
competitors, the AI citations, and the
traditional search. And you can see
here, this is the byproduct. So,
basically, I do it in four different
tabs. One is going to be competitors, so
this this is directly who's actually
being mentioned in the AI platforms when
these queries are being searched, right?
What is the AI recommending or putting
into that answer, okay? This is
traditional search, right? Just your
standard traditional search looking
across multiple search platforms, four
to be exact. And then also the AI
platforms, as you can tell. These are
the citations that are used in the AI
platforms. These are not the answers.
These are citations. What is used in
retrieval? Okay, so you need all of
these things because what you want to do
is you want to create what I call blend.
And this blend is really helpful. So
what I've done is I basically took those
two reports, put them into one solid
Google sheet like this, and this gives
me a lay of the land of opportunities
for us to go and attack across the
board, across every unique intent. So
I'll just show you an example of this.
So when you look at this, we're looking
at approximately This is just a short ex
If this was a campaign we're actually
running, I'd probably do at least a
thousand opportunities. But that's
because when you have a thousand
opportunities across traditional search
and AI citations, you're going to have
to dedupe, right? So when you dedupe,
you're going to have much less than
that. An example of this, we'll go ahead
and look at this.
And let's go ahead and sort it by URL,
okay? And we're going to find that
there's going to be some URLs that are
going to pop up in traditional search
and AI. So this is a really good
example, right? They show up in Brave
and Google Organic, and also show up in
Grok, okay? This doesn't mean I'm going
to eliminate this row, but it's it is
interesting to see, right? We want to
see that. So really what I'm looking
for, believe it or not, is like who are
the brands that continue to show up over
and over, the domains that continue to
show up all the time. And those are the
ones I really want to flag, right? And
because we know that if those continue
to show up in traditional search and
show up as a core source of retrieval,
that's a place where we want our brand
to be, okay? So what I'll do here is let
me add another column. I'm going to add
a checkbox, and we'll run this. Let's
see. And basically, this will be our
just a very simple way to flag these
opportunities to go after them, okay? So
we'll just call it opportunity. And
we'll go ahead and do this. Want it to
be centered. All right, let's move this
over, and I want to look specifically
right here, okay? So very unlikely we're
going to be able to get any coverage on
some of these RP, not very likely, okay?
So don't flag things where you basically
have no chance. It's just not going to
be worth your time. Obviously Amazon,
that's that would be an owned asset that
you'd want to go and build on Amazon. So
certainly could just mark Amazon. AOL,
there's probably opportunity here for a
sponsored post. I would imagine these
are probably sponsored posts more than
likely. So yeah, so this is all
sponsored content and it actually
distributed from New York Post. So you
basically go to New York Post, do a
sponsored post, and you can ultimately
promote your product. So First Form
could have easily been in this, but they
just need to go and pursue these
sponsored post opportunities. But in AI
we often see a lot of sponsored content
showing up and influencing the answers.
It's very common. So it doesn't matter
whether it's paid or organic. It just
simply does not matter. This one here,
let's take a look and it looks like
Yeah, it looks like these guys
they're promoting one specific type of
product and it looks like Yeah. So this
is a good opportunity too where you
could reach out and build a partnership
with this particular entity. Okay? I'm
looking at the entities that are getting
cited and obviously you should
prioritize the ones that have the most
citations. That's really what matters or
that are being that have the most
visibility across these different
surfaces. And then those should be your
priority. Okay? And you can see there's
a lot. Like this one here looks like
Garage Gym Reviews. You can see they're
actually getting tons of coverage for
creatine. Look at this. They're
basically in all these platforms. So
this is definitely a website I would
want to focus in on. Coming down here,
we got Good Housekeeping. Once again,
they have good coverage. Go down here.
Obviously Healthline. Want to try to do
[clears throat] something sponsored
there for sure.
And then just so on and so forth, right?
We got Men's Health, obviously goes
without saying. They're all over the
place. And this is what you do, right?
You want to keep attacking this. Now you
start to see some some ones like Reddit
as well. You want to go after Reddit and
you can do this There's a lot of ways to
go about doing this. I won't get too
deep into Reddit strategy, but there's
ways to get into Reddit, okay? There's
plenty of people that have aged accounts
that will go and promote your products
in these various threads. So, if you're
trying to prioritize which threads to go
after, always prioritize the threads
that are already showing up in
retrieval, okay? But, also keeping a
pulse on these general subreddits as
well and constantly every day if you see
opportunities, you should be jumping on
those early, right? Really early cuz a
lot of these are established threads.
Sometimes they're closed. Sometimes you
can't contribute to them. So, that's why
it's critical that you first attack
these cuz we know they're being used in
retrieval. Then second secondly, you're
on a daily basis watching and then
trying to contribute as fast as
possible, okay? And so, this is the
technique that you wanted use because
what you're doing is you're basically
just looking at what is what already has
visibility and this is all you that you
have to do. Another good one actually
here is YouTube. So, on YouTube is
interesting because you can technically
[clears throat] target existing videos
and have them promote inside of an
existing video in the description or
even in the pin comment, but it's a
little bit it's not as effective cuz
often times you'd be promoting on a
probably a video that's going to be
declining in views in most cases cuz
most generally most older videos are in
decline, not in acceleration of views.
But, what you want to do is actually
look at the channels that are talking
about this topic a lot, right? This
particular channel here looks like they
talk about creatine quite a bit or we go
and we investigate and see. So, we'll go
ahead and take a look and see if they
actually do talk about creatine. So, it
looks like he's talking about creatine.
So, we'll go to his channel. We'll go to
videos and then we'll just do a quick
search and see how often they talk about
creatine. And a lot, right? They talk
about creatine quite a bit. So, this
would be a perfect one to explore and
ultimately try to get brand coverage
here and you would do it just by
building partnership, right? So, this is
the process that you want to follow as
far as the citations.
>> [clears throat]
>> The citations are the work, okay? So,
when you think about AI search
optimization, this is it, right? This is
really the focus because the more
coverage you can get on these core
sources of retrieval, these most
important entities, the better you're
going to perform. It's basically it
works so well as long as you are getting
coverage. Now, the thing is, the best
thing to do is obviously begin working
on this right away, but the second best
thing to do is use your website as one
of the core sources of retrieval and use
your own assets once again as a core
source of retrieval. So, in the case of
First Form, I would take advantage of
the fact that they have a really strong
social media presence, really strong
profiles, and I would go on the attack
as far as creatine, okay? So, what I've
showed you so far is kind of I'm going
on order here, but extract citation
opportunities, okay? So, going back to
the five stages of customer awareness,
this is where we're going to begin this
attack process. But in general, in a
case like this, it's pretty obvious what
you want to go after, especially
[clears throat]
at the solution aware phase, which is
basically all those queries we've
already covered, which is best creatine
for the specific use case, right? So,
basically we just paste these in and
these are directly from the AI chat, but
more than likely if we were to search
these, they're probably going to have
some sort of volume, but this is a good
base to begin. You don't want to go too
crazy here because there's going to be a
lot to go after on this front, but
basically this is like the center of the
work that you're going to be doing. So,
this would be in the solution aware
phase, okay? So, then here, what we're
going to be doing is actually sorry,
this will stay in the solution aware,
would be the competitors specifically.
Now, this is where things get a little
tricky with clients because clients
don't always want to talk about their
competitors,
but I'm telling you if you want to
perform well in these AI platforms,
unfortunately, you will have to do it.
You will have to compare yourself to
your competitors. And if you don't do
it, your competitors are probably going
to do it, and the consumers you're going
to let the consumers make that decision.
I would much rather be in control of the
situation. So, what you can do here is
you can look at the top competitors, all
right? So, this I pulled this directly
from that report, and these are all the
top competitors. And what I'll do is
just filter this, and we're just going
to see what are the competitors that
just seem to keep showing up everywhere,
okay? For all these different variants.
And we can quickly see just at a quick
glance and see who are the ones that
keep showing up. So, these guys right
here,
they're showing up a lot, right? They're
showing up a ton across basically many
different types of intent, which means
they have authority in this particular
category. What we're really looking for
are the like five to 10 biggest
competitors in this one category. We're
not trying to look at everything, just
this one single category, okay? And then
from there, we're going to be able to
basically reverse engineer what they've
done to beat them, okay? So, this is
where we want to begin our process. And
ultimately, we need to build a strategy
of comparison techniques. So, what that
means is we're basically going to take a
brand like this, okay? And I'm just
going to go ahead and look them up. So,
this is the challenge when you start to
go into a specific category, you'll
often find specific competitors that
they only do this one thing, right? And
that makes them even harder to beat. And
you can see here, this is just what they
do. They just do creatine. So, to beat
them, you have to go as intense as they
have done, right? But, the biggest thing
that's probably going to help them is
that they have a slight partial match
domain and a partial match brand name.
So, they're definitely one I would have
want to pay attention to, but this also
brings up another important point that
is
it might be a situation where you would
potentially, just an idea, want to spawn
off a micro brand specifically for
creatine and have a dedicated website
just for creatine. That's something that
can be really effective because you can
basically just really tap into that that
relevance. So, the main reason why you
want to find your competitors because
you're going to formulate different
queries to attack these different
competitor queries. And these are so
incredibly powerful if you want to drive
conversions.
But most importantly, whenever someone
is searching for, let's say something
like in ChatGPT, they're searching for
something like best creatine. We can
even run this. I'll just run a manual
example so you can see what happens in
this case. So, we'll just do Let's go
ahead and run like Let's see, go to the
queries over here. Let's do one that's
very specific. So, like best creatine
for Let's do vegans. We'll do that one.
So, we're going to go into ChatGPT and I
want you to watch how ChatGPT
does this. So, we'll go incognito and
then we're going to run this, okay? And
basically, you're going to watch how
ChatGPT uses retrieval. And so, two
things that happened, if you're not
familiar with the systems that occur
here, when you run a query in ChatGPT,
the first thing that happens is that the
large language model looks in what is
called its static corpus, which is its
training data, and sees if it already
knows the answer to this question. But,
in a lot of cases, in fact, almost every
query these days is
when it doesn't know the answer based on
its training data, it goes and does
retrieval. And we see that retrieval's
used just more often than not
and that's because basically what's
happening is these AI platforms have
learned that the base knowledge, the
model training, is really But, what
makes it more intelligent more
intelligent is having grounding on top
of it. So, to get grounding, it has to
go and do web search and find
information. So, based on what we're
seeing here, this is exactly what you
would expect. We're going to see
specific brands that are mentioned here.
But, the part I want you to really get
focused in on is right here, okay? And
the reason is because when you see how
and Chat GPT doesn't fully reveal how it
goes out and does web search, but we can
get a pretty good idea just by looking
at the citations that tend to appear
here, okay? We can see all of these
different citations that pop up. And a
lot of them are usually listical-based
citations just because of the nature of
how we searched in general. So, let's
see here. See if there's any verses in
here. So, there's a few verses, but
they're not specifically brand verse
brand, so this probably isn't a common
practice in this industry, which means
it's wide open, okay? So, a company like
First Form, and obviously, you need to
feel very confident about your products,
right? But if you're confident about
your products, you think you have good
positioning in the market, these are the
queries you want to be going you want to
be going after, okay? If you want to
really build that strong topic authority
around this one category, you have to do
this. There's a few different types of
queries I like to use. The first is
alternatives, okay? So, you can see
here, let's say Legion creatine
alternatives. That's one of my
favorites, right? So, you build a whole
list. Obviously, if you believe this to
be true and there's evidence that it's
true, you put yourself as number one,
and then you put the competitors
anywhere between seven to 10 competitors
in there, and then you build a list,
okay? Very simple. Then the next one is
a review. So, specific review of this
product. Now, the thing is, I want to
make it clear, like you don't have to be
nasty in these, right? You can still
give objective differences between the
products. Maybe you got different ways
that you construct those products. Like,
you can find things that are objectively
different, and but they're not like
nasty, "Hey, yeah, their product sucks
and we're better." Like, that's not what
you want to do. You want to make it
clean. You can still do this in a nice
way, and that's what you want to do. So,
basically, there's a few different ones
you want to do. You want to do the
review, so I'll just write these down
here so you can see the different
variants. So, it's going to be
competitor, like this, review. I mean,
actually, I'll go down so you can see
from how the this goes down in search
intent. So, we'll take it from where we
started, which is best creatine for
vegans, okay? Then what's going to
happen is it's going to be in this list,
right? On a post like this, there's
going to be a bunch of competitors that
are listed. So, then we want to attack
each competitor review, right? From
there. Then what we want to do is we
want to go after same thing, which would
be competitor alternatives, okay? And
this works in every industry. I've tried
this across every single industry, it
just works, okay? And then this one here
would be competitor verse competitor.
Now, this one is the most interesting
because a lot of people ignore these,
right? So, you'll see these pop up in
Google Search Console all the time and
you'll see these queries. What you can
do is you can take this query and you
can just slap you
on it. Like that, okay? And that's what
I did right here where you can see I did
creatine battle, okay? And so, this
looks Legion verse Thorne verse First
Form. And what I've done here is I'm
getting the relevance of creatine, so I
don't have to repeat it for all three of
the brands, but I'm still getting that
brand element in there. So, this is
specifically focused on their creatine
product lines at each of these brands,
okay? So, this helps you get the best of
both worlds. This is a keyword, Ahrefs
verse NeuronWriter, okay? But take a
look at this. Rankability, the number
one cited source for this query and the
number one result for this query, okay?
So, just to show you how powerful this
is and look at what I did. All I did was
slapped on Rankability on the end of
this, right? So, we built out This is
actually the target query, which is
NeuronWriter verse Ahrefs, but I just
slap on Rankability at the end and I get
the best of both worlds, right? I get to
rank for all their stuff and also get to
add some comparison elements for our
brand inside of there. This just works
so well. Just published this one
recently. Scrunch AI verse Profound.
This is just a couple of days ago, all
right? And we'll see if it's ranking and
boom, it's right there. Already on the
first page, 15 hours ago, okay? 15 hours
ago, already showing up. Once again, I
don't include rankability in the query,
but this is the focus. The query is the
competitors, right? So, you can do this.
It's incredibly powerful, and not a lot
of people do this. Okay, so those are
the those are like the three core, and
then obviously the next one
that makes a lot of sense is would be
competitor verse obviously you. Now,
just with these alone, you can see how
many opportunities there truly are,
right? There's so many opportunities
when you build this out, and that's why
I just did a small example of this just
to prove this point, but look at how
many queries we have just with these
variants, okay? We're looking at 71
different pages that need to be built on
the website. 71, and then we're just
scratching the surface. This is 19
different kind of core unique intents,
but there's a lot of other intents you
could build out for sure. You go deeper
and deeper. So, with Google Search
Console, it's amazing because once you
start pushing these assets out, more
queries are going to flood Search
Console, and you're going to start to
see those unique variants, and you can
start attacking it even more, and the
end result is that you can just build so
much topic authority in that one
category. People greatly underestimate
how much it takes to build true topic
authority. It takes a lot, and you have
to hit so many different
types of intents. So, that's what we're
doing here. We're basically we're
attacking these topics with everything
we have. This is basically what query
fan out is. When you put something in
the AI, like best creatine for vegans,
is this simple all the time. It'll
actually conduct a very simple query,
then it will go and say, "Okay, once the
AI has identified, let's say five
brands, then it will actually go and run
a lot of these similar same queries."
Very common. Search is just like a
human. So, essentially we're modeling
what the AI already does, and by us
continually showing up over and over,
that's what influences the AI platforms
a lot. And if you need proof of this,
I'll just show you. This is like a
real-life example. Okay, I'll just show
you. I just did this recently just to
prove how powerful this can be. HubSpot
launched a brand new tool in the AEO
space. He said, "We're going to go after
HubSpot AEO." So, what do you
immediately launched several assets, and
you can see in traditional search,
right? We've got one, we've got a
LinkedIn post, which I'll explain the
parasite SEO component of this. We've
got one, two, and we go down here, then
we've got another asset for Rankability,
then YouTube, and then the LinkedIn post
again. So, you know, we've got Well,
let's see we've got how many? We've got
five. Five of the top 30 positions
across all these search engines, okay?
That's a lot. 17%
ownership of the SERPs just for this one
query. But then we go into the answers,
and you can see Rankability.
Think about how crazy this is for a
second, okay? Rankability, we're
completely bootstrapped. All right,
we're completely bootstrapped. We have
three team members. That is it. It's me,
Simon, and Amber, okay? That's it. These
companies that we're showing up near,
Profound, they have a billion-dollar
valuation, okay? You did just check this
out. Profound funding, okay? $96 million
in funding in February, which put them
in a billion-dollar valuation, okay?
It's unheard of that we should even be
in the conversation with them, okay?
Because they can crush us as far as the
resources. So, how are we doing this?
The These companies are well-funded, so
how is it possible that Rankability
continues to show up for all of these
queries that obviously they would like
to show up for as well. The reason is
because we're deploying a very proven
strategy. And this is a strategy we've
been developing over the last couple of
years, and it continues to get better
and better. And it's very simple. We
attack these queries with everything
that we have, okay? Everything that we
have. So, we got the traditional search
attack, then we're attacking citations,
and as you can see, using our website,
using using LinkedIn, right? That's what
we're doing. Okay, and this is how you
can really attack these queries, HubSpot
AEO alternatives, but I want you to take
a look at this, okay? So, we'll go into
Google and I want to show you how
powerful this can be. HubSpot, and
you'll see look at I'm I'm actually
eating our own dog food, okay? What I'm
telling you to do is what we do. It's
right here. You can see it. And every
single one of these pages ranks, every
single one. But, the way to build this
hyper focused topic relevance is you
have to attack this just one query at a
time. And keep in mind, the bigger
objective here is to build topic
authority for AEO, but you do it by
getting granular first and then going
upward, right? That's the way that we
personally do it. So, just want to show
you the power of this, how well this can
work if you do this the right way. Now,
of course, you have to feel comfortable
talking about your competitors. I would
highly recommend it, all right? So,
those are the queries I think you
understand what we're doing here, which
is the five stages customer awareness.
Now, this aligns really well with the
topic domination plan, okay? So, you
begin with your website, you tackle the
queries on your website, okay? It's the
first thing you want to do. But, then
you got to figure out what's the next
best platform to attack these topics
again, okay? Your website's just one
part of the equation. Next is like, all
right, well, if we're going to build
topic authority around creatine for
vegans, we got the one on our site,
we're attacking all the competitors,
where's the next best place? You want to
go the places that have really good
indexation in traditional search. So,
we'll just first form. All right, so we
can see they're indexed. Now, normally,
if you weren't sure, you could just copy
this if you weren't sure, and then you
just go into Google,
and you can drop the URL, and then just
see how well their recent videos are
getting indexed. And if they're getting
indexed well, then that's a good place
to start because you know that it's
going to get crawled and indexed fast,
and then it's going to be used in this
topic authority equation that we're
trying to build, okay? So, this is a
really good place to start. So, for me
it's very simple. So, you can see same
exact topics on YouTube. Same exact.
Now, it gets definitely a little more
awkward on YouTube if you're going to go
after your competitor, so I would say
for these I might put maybe or something
like that because these are a little
more you may want to go and sponsor some
videos to attack these instead of do
this on your channel, but I'd say at
least for these this is a yes, like
absolute yes. Attack these with
everything you got. These are all the
ones that you want to go after, okay?
Because this is even with just these
alone, it's about 21 videos that you
could build out all around the creatine
segment, right? So, just imagine you've
got your website, then you've got
YouTube which is the second most popular
website on the internet, and now you're
just you're really starting to build
that infrastructure for dominance around
that topic, okay? But, then you want to
go to the next level. Next one is you
just run these same exact queries again
this time on LinkedIn, right? And you
can actually do this. We'll look
specifically at LinkedIn
cuz LinkedIn's a really good parasite
website. And you can see they're doing
really well, right? We can see this.
We'll copy this over, and then take this
to the next level, all right? So, this
is where you can start to get pretty
crazy with this, but I just want to show
you, all right? So, we got First Form
and we're seeing that they're getting
indexed. They got plenty of indexation
as far as the brand. And then on top of
it
what you can do is basically the way
that we would do it is we would take one
of these topics, so it'd be like we'll
continue with a vegan one. So, we'll go
best creatine for vegans, all right? So,
this would be LinkedIn, all right? So,
we go on LinkedIn and we would attack
this query on the company page, all
right? So, it's supplements for vegans,
and I would say specifically
2026. So, we got that. So, it's timely,
all right? So, we would publish this
article on the company page, all right,
that's the first part. Then, when that
is published, the next best move is to
amplify this content with employees.
Okay? So, then you have all of your
employees share that article. So, what
that's going to do is going to create a
lot of different routes into that
article. Lots of different opportunities
to to push the crawling and the
indexation. This is what you want. And
the more employees you have that have at
least a little bit of authority on
LinkedIn, the better it's going to be.
So, like an example would be Sal, for
example, who's the CEO and he he's got
5,000 followers. So, he's a very good
person to either share this or at least
like it or add He needs to drive signals
to this page. Okay? Cuz you want to get
it indexed. And LinkedIn is just
stupidly powerful. Okay? I'll show you
an example of this in traditional search
for this query. LinkedIn is number four.
Okay? Let's see on Google, it's number
six. Bing, it's four. DuckDuckGo, it's
three. And Brave, it's 14. So, it's not
doing as well there. But, across these
other ones, you can see it's the fourth
most visible URL for this query.
LinkedIn, right? And now I'll just show
you the article. It's basically a slight
variant of the core article that's on
our website, right? You can see. It's a
fine article. It gets the job done. But,
you see everything I'm doing is I'm just
pushing people right back into back to
the website, right? And then, of course,
embedding more of the other assets that
we have. Okay? So, that's what you want
to do. So, you would attack this exactly
that way on LinkedIn. You build Once
again, you just drive more visibility to
that and you rinse and repeat over and
over. We'll remove the most aware.
And just by doing the website, YouTube,
and LinkedIn, all with your owned
assets, we're looking at 163
assets to publish. And it's basically
all on similar stuff, so you should be
able to pump these out pretty easily for
the most part with a little bit of
focus. For First
the thing is they've also got like a big
presence on other platforms as well. So,
they've got TikTok. Like I would attack
TikTok absolutely. Same exact topics
again, but in a micro content form. We
would also do it again on Instagram,
right? So, we got Instagram here. It
looks like they're getting good
indexation as well here on Instagram.
So, once again, very easy thing to to
attack. And that just multiplies. So,
that'd be just with those distribution
channels, we're looking at 200 assets
all around creatine to build topic
authority. And this is many years ago
was a big focus on building topical
authority. And a lot of that was really
focused on the website and also maybe a
little bit with on the backlink profile.
I kind of termed this thing topic
domination because I found how powerful
this was because I originally discovered
this when I started ranking for stuff
like Star SEO agency. And like I would
just show up
And you can see it's They show up in the
videos here, another one here, and then
you go down here, you got another one
LinkedIn, which was a year ago, and then
more videos, and so on and so forth,
okay? That's where I started to see
this. It's just cuz my experience on
YouTube. I was like, "Oh my gosh, I
wonder if like I could just try to like
capture as many spots as possible." And
this has translated really well over to
AI AI search specifically. So, that is
the topic domination plan. That's how
you want to go about doing this. And
this just it just works. The problem is
most people just don't want to do it
because it's hard, right?
You got to produce 200 pieces of
content. But truthfully, it's a lot of
work, but this is what it takes to
dominate a category. So, just imagine if
you were First Form, and you attacked
every category this way, right? Every
category, you go on offense in this way.
This is what it takes, right? Especially
when you think about all these different
categories. They're trying to come
They're try They're fighting a lot of
battles on many different fronts, okay?
And so to win, they really got to get
focused. Okay, they got the products in
place, but now you got to get super
focused in on some categories. And like
I said, it can take a one quarter,
sometimes two quarters to to really fill
in that whole topic to the extent where
like okay, I think we've covered
creatine enough. I think we can move on
to collagen, okay? Now, what I've showed
you today is really just about your
owned assets, all right? So now what
we're going to start thinking about is
what about off of the website? Okay, now
this is where things go to the next
level, all right? So what we've really
done here is we've attacked all of the
core topics
across our major owned assets. So an
example here is so we'll say for our
owned assets, we've attacked
We've got the website, we've got
YouTube, we've got LinkedIn, we've got
Instagram, we've also got TikTok. Okay,
so that's five, all right? So five
different distribution channels,
assuming we're going to hit most of
these, we're going to be looking at
roughly when you consider the
amplification of posts that will be
promoting the other assets on LinkedIn
and maybe other areas too. You do the
ones on every platform, all right? If
you post on YouTube, get your team
members to engage with those videos. If
you post on TikTok, get your team
members to engage with the ones on
TikTok to amplify it even more. But
we're talking like it could be nearly
250 to 500 assets just around your owned
ecosystem. Honestly, this could be
enough to move the needle. And
considering where they currently are as
far as performance, doing this alone
will make things better. Just doing this
and nothing else, it's almost a
guarantee to see performance gains,
okay? But the next thing I'm going to be
looking at is okay, aside from our owned
assets, where's the next best place to
build topic authority around creatine?
Simply just look at these top
competitors here and see who's popping
up the most. Healthline is the number
one most cited domain, right? And number
one most cited entity as well. So, this
is where I would want to spend my time,
right? I try to go to Healthline and see
if we can get sponsored content. So,
really what I would do is I'd actually
go over to the to the blend that we
built and we're going to look
specifically at Let's look specifically
at Healthline. Go down here.
And yeah, they're crushing it. You look
at these They're They basically show up
for every single query related to
creatine. Okay, every single one. So,
the first method I would try because
this is the most impactful method. Let's
go ahead and clear this out and then
we'll just look at Healthline only. So,
the first method I would attempt to do
is
I would like to focus on the
pages that have a lot of visibility. So,
this one here, which best creatine,
okay?
So, let's see here. Six best creatine
monohydrate supplements. All right, so
basically what I would try to do is I
would reach out, try to find whoever the
contact is at Healthline, and we would
try to see if we could be included as
another option here and see what the
criteria is for a brand to show up in
this process, okay? Because this is
truly one of the most critical pages
that you can get a citation on. So, it
is worth whatever it takes to be here,
okay? Literally whatever it takes.
Financially, giving product away, like
reaching out to as many people as
possible, building relationships with
the contacts here, like everything,
okay? But you should really think about
Healthline as like one of your core
channels that you have to go after with
everything you have, okay? Because you
look at the distribution of strength
they have across so many different
platforms. Look at this. These are all
the different platforms that they're
showing up on all the time, okay? So,
you have to do this, okay? It's so
important. So, that's the next part of
this is like offsite, all right?
Offsite. And we'll call it earned just
because we're not So, first one is
Healthline, like as far as you're going
to prioritize, that's where I'd begin.
So, you say like priority one, okay? So,
the most important would be one, all
right? So, that's our first priority.
Then we just go right back over to the
tracker again and we look at, okay, so
Reddit, Amazon, we're going to go over
here and we're going to see if they have
their creatine on Amazon and it looks
like
not seeing their creatine on Amazon. So,
that's probably some sort of decision
that they've made to not sell the
creatine on Amazon, but it looks like
they sell other things on Amazon. So, it
looks like they're just not selling
their creatine specifically. So, that's
a huge opportunity, right? They're
willing to do some selling through
Amazon, which is like the number one
e-commerce platform on the planet, I
would highly recommend that.
>> [laughter]
>> So, let's clear this out. We're going to
go to Amazon and you can see how much
visibility Amazon has for these critical
topics as well, okay? So, once again,
just for the earned alone, we're looking
at Healthline, so we got Healthline in
here. We've got Amazon, which is another
channel that we can attack for this
specific topic. And then, the next one
that we would want to consider, too, of
course, Reddit, okay? Reddit shows up
for everything and Forbes and Garage Gym
Reviews, so all of these, okay? I'm not
going to go through all of them, but
this is the process you want to go
through. And just looking at this, like
just the top 10 alone, because they have
so much influence across these queries,
this would change the game completely.
Like even if you got just 20% brand
coverage across the top 10 entities or
domains, it's almost guaranteed to move
the needle. And and considering the the
bar is pretty low right now, it could
move very fast. So, we We that figured
out. We've created our benchmark
reports, we've identified top
competitors, category level comparison,
that's all good. All right, so now at
this point, we've focused a lot on
strategy. So, we've got our basically
our owned content strategy, we've got
our earned content strategy, or our
earned outreach strategy, whatever you
want to call it, all established. All
right, so let's just take let's go ahead
and we'll start with the website here.
And we want to do this in a very
intelligent way. All right, this is very
important. We don't just want to
haphazardly do this, we want to be
really smart about our strategy. So, in
the case of best creatine for vegans,
okay, so first thing I would do is let's
verify I've got a lot of tabs up here,
so let me kind of chop this up a little
bit. So, first thing I'm going to verify
is I'm going to do Psycholean
First Form plus vegan, and we'll see
what pops up for this. Okay, so they got
it looks like some blog content, looks
like they have some protein powder.
Let's do vegan creatine.
See if there's anything in here,
vegan-friendly supplements. Okay, it
looks like they've got maybe a category
page that does have this, but once
again,
not specific to creatine, okay? So, in
this case, the best method I would use
here to not have to build out another
category page, which would be kind of
pointless cuz you basically have like
just it'd be duplicated with the
creatine category, I would absolutely do
this on the blog. And so, what I would
do here is let's go over to create, and
let's go here. So, this would be a fresh
asset that you would build from scratch.
So, in this way,
I would do best creatine for vegans, so
that would be the first part. We got
English, so this will be US by default
unless you change it. And then in the
custom instructions,
I would say something like rank First
Form's creatine as the number one
creatine for vegans. Okay, so this is
just the first step, just to give it a
little bit of grounding of what we're
trying to achieve with this piece of
content. So, that's the first part.
Second part is the system will
automatically detect that the intent, so
that is the correct intent, which would
be discover.
And then you want to identify what
search research platforms you want to
use. For me, I like to overkill it. You
don't have to do this, you could just do
Google, but what this does is going to
extract the top ranking competitors in
Google. Actually, what we've done
basically today with that extraction was
traditional search and then pulling the
AI citations as well, okay? So, we're
going to go ahead and run this and
basically it'll take you to a second
step and this is part's really important
because what you want to do is you want
to put your unique selling propositions
in here, okay? So, what I would do is
probably just do something like we'll go
back over to advisor and let's see here.
So, I'm just going to copy this over to
advisor and I'm going to say, "Answer
this for our copywriter brief and tell
us how First Form has unique
differentiation against its
competitors." It only needs to be
between three to four sentences, okay?
Now, I'm
using my mic to speak this through,
okay? So, we can see here, okay, and
then we could say, "Give me five to 10
unique differentiators for First Form's
creatine versus the competitors." Just
put it in a simple list. Sometimes you
got to direct the AI a little bit more
on this. But, this should ultimately
give us something we can work with.
Okay, yeah, this is perfect. This is
exactly what we want. All right, so
we're going to copy this over. All
right, let's see. Yeah, okay, we don't
need that. Let's see here. Okay, yeah,
some of this stuff I wouldn't do, but
for just for the sake of doing this,
we'll just throw this in, okay? And
basically what this will do is it will
analyze to see if this is actually
anything unique that would be useful,
okay? And we'll have to make sure some
clarification. This is for First Form,
which should be the number one
recommended brand in this listicle. So,
normally this would be much more
developed, but in this case we've got
creatine supplements in here, which is
perfectly fine for the situation. Okay,
so we're going to go ahead and run that
now. And basically what will happen here
is it's going to go and do research
across all of these search platforms.
It's going to extract the relevant
topics and entities and their content
structure. It's going to extract their
word counts. And then what it's going to
do is going to come back with a content
brief that's based on all of that
relevance. And also based on being on
brand. Okay. Now, one thing I didn't do
cuz this isn't an actual campaign I'm
working on, but if I would normally have
done this in my initial setup is I would
have set up the brand voice as well. So,
you go into settings, you go to brand
voice. And basically you can just in
this case I'll just do an auto fi- auto
fill on this one. But, you set up the
brand voice specifically for whatever
one you're working on and this will be
used in the actual content itself. Okay,
so you can see this. This filled out
really easily. Very good. And this is
all good stuff. And in fact, it actually
was able to identify competitors, which
is quite impressive. For brand terms,
definitely want to put in
First Form. Probably want to put in any
associated entities with this brands,
Andy Frisella, who's one of the
founders. Put him in there. It's always
a good thing. And this just makes
overall your campaign a lot more
effective. All right. So, let's go ahead
and take a look and see how this is
doing. Okay, so the brief is ready to
go. So, what you can see here is what
happened is it went ahead and used the
knowledge base, created the obviously a
very good title tag, nice little meta
description, a suggested URL. I do agree
with this. Yep, that's the one I would
personally use. You can see the entities
that we would want to cover in this
content. This is based on the
competitors, but also based on when the
AI reads all of this different content.
It could be anywhere between 50 to 75
articles or pages. The AI will also
identify gaps across all the competitors
and will make suggestions in here as
well. Now, what we're going to look at
here is exactly what we want to see is a
perfect goal listical format for this
particular query. So,
the only thing I would change is
probably just add the actual number in
here, but aside from that, this will get
the job done. And we can see it
perfectly placed first form exactly
where we wanted it to be right at the
beginning. And then we've got some of
these other competitors that are popping
up in here as well. So, this is exactly
what we want to see. But then it also
shows the people also ask. So, this is a
way to tap into query funnel, like I
mentioned earlier in this video, which
would allow this one asset to rank not
just for its core keyword or core topic,
but also those secondary topics, more
long-tail traffic. Once this gets
published, we will measure the
performance of these dedicated queries
that will probably be in the FAQ
section, see how they're performing, and
then if they're underperforming, we can
always splinter off and build a
dedicated asset around that topic. Okay.
So,
keep going down here. A nice internal
link, very good. Yep, that's definitely
something we want to see. Probably want
to add another internal link to like the
category page. So, just to kind of get
that link equity and authority flowing
back to the core category. So, I would
definitely want to get that in there as
well. So, let's see here. So, we'll pop
that in. And we could just we could put
something like creatine mono. Actually,
you know, we'll just keep it creatine.
We'll keep it broad in this case. Okay.
All right. And then from there, we're
just going to generate the draft. So,
what will happen is this will generate
directly from the brief. So, the brief
is the foundation of the draft. Okay, so
the draft is ready to go. So, we can see
here a couple things right away. I
haven't even touched this just first
draft out of the gate. You can see that
it's covered the topics pretty well.
Okay, so we've got we're looking at
about 66 entities and topics that are
covered. It covered pretty much what
you'd want to see. But we can go ahead
and flip this over to unused, and you
can see there's more opportunity to
attack more queries if you want. Now,
you could do it in this asset itself, or
one thing we like to do, too, is look at
these as additional content
opportunities, right? And you can use
these as seeds to then expand out
further to build more semantic relevance
around this one topic. Now, based on
what I'm seeing here, this looks pretty
solid. The only thing I would say is
this is a little bulky, so you want to
kind of split this up a little bit, just
so that it's a little more readable. One
thing that we recently added is that
we've included a new step in this
process that does additional web search
outside of just competitor analysis. So,
what you see here is purely competitor
analysis. Basically, we're extracting
from the top competitors, extracting all
their stuff, but then a layer on top of
this is additional web research to
clarify some facts. And so, you can see
this is an example where it actually
went and retrieved information from
somewhere to verify some information in
here. So, very high-quality stuff. And
this is literally the first draft. You
should definitely improve it. And we
even see little details right here, like
contact for pricing.
This is something that you don't want to
have in the listicle. You need to have
very specific numbers in here. And this
is just basically the AI playing it safe
in some cases, but we see there's a
bunch of other situations here where it
went and found actual, you know,
retrievable facts to make sure this
information is accurate, okay? So,
[snorts] we can see here this is a
perfect type of listicle that you would
want to build out. At the end here, you
can see we've got those secondary topics
here with the FAQ, where it actually
going to help build out that query fan
out process. So, like I said, this is a
first draft. You need to treat it as a
first draft. Typically, any AI draft
that we have is typically going to go
through anywhere between three to five
iterations before going to production.
But, this is a very good place to start
is all I'm saying. So, basically, what
we would do from here is we would repeat
this process for every single asset that
we're going to build. The same process I
just followed, same exact process to
attack this every time. And these will
not be duplicate, by the way, because
every single one of these queries is
going to surface a different set of
competitors. And by servicing a
different set of competitors, this
listical is inherently going to be
different nearly every single time that
you do this. So, if you're doing one for
best creatine for sensitive stomachs,
it's going to be an entirely different
set of retrieval sources. So, it's
always going to be different, okay? The
next angle's going to be about
specifically sensitive stomach, okay?
So, you want to repeat that process over
and over. So, at this point, we have
officially figured out the content
development process. It's just a matter
of execution now. Just build out the
assets and publish them. Make sure that
you're internally linking the assets
together, okay? So, every time you
publish a article about vegan, you want
to internally link that to another asset
about creatine, and just get everything
linking together, but putting the
category page at the center of that
core, and everything else is built to
support that category page. And then,
the next one here is very simple thing
that we will will do for existing
contents. The last kind of point here is
you will go and So, inside of this
section here, you can go ahead and go to
the optimize. So, that one we just ran
is a pure op standard route. This
optimize route, you actually can look at
a specific URL and do an extraction. So,
that's what you're looking at right
here. So, you can see this is an
extraction of their category page, and
you can see there's some room for
improvement, right? There's some room
for improvement on this one. So, it's
not covering a lot of the critical
topics that need to be covered on this
page, and that's something that
obviously want to address, okay? So,
that would be the first thing. Next
thing is run that same page through the
page-level analysis. So, we've got
inside of our audit section over here.
They've got the domain-level analysis,
but then the page-level analysis. This
is the best page-level audit on the
market. There is no other page-level
audit that's at this level. I can
guarantee it, because we cover more than
any other thing could. This is like
99.9% of the variables you would ever
need to cover on a page to make sure
that it's built to perform in search or
or even as a source of retrieval, okay?
It's focused on a few different things.
If you do this right, if you follow the
recommendations on here, you're going to
do well in traditional search, you're
going to do well as a source of
retrieval when AI does web research, and
then you're also going to increase your
odds of being actually baked into the
models because there's a little new
section here about Common Crawl. But
basically, run the page through and it's
going to look at all these important
categories. So crawling, indexing, could
be looking at the content itself and
seeing how well it's optimized. This is
the topic coverage, on-page structure,
basic stuff, looking at content
freshness, okay? So that actually is a
big piece of this. We know that AI
platforms prefer fresher pages typically
in retrieval.
And then file freshness, this is
something I love to do, but basically go
to any page like this and you go to view
page source, and I love to look for
really outdated stuff. 2023, maybe 2022.
Yep, so we're starting to see some
outdated stuff popping up in here, okay?
Remember, these platforms are looking at
code, okay? They're looking at code.
They don't care how pretty your website
is, especially the AI platforms. They
deconstruct your websites down to its
most basic fundamentals. And so you want
to make sure that everything is up to
date. Not just the copy, but every
single little detail, your images, the
code, everything. So that's what this
little variable is looking at. And then
UX and performance, it's well documented
that in traditional search, fast-loading
pages are good and are important. These
AI platforms do not mess around. If you
have a slow-loading page, you're going
to be in trouble, okay? So this is
definitely something you want to get
focused in on. And then page quality
score,
we basically take the content and run it
through our own proprietary process to
have the AI assess that page. It's based
on Google's helpful content guidelines.
So you can see here that it's there's
opportunity. But, the biggest one is
specifically making it ready for the
future or not even the future, the
reality of today, which is agent
searching. And I think approximately 60%
of all searches now are actually agents.
It means when someone's using ChatGPT
and ChatGPT does not know the answer, it
uses agents to go and find that
information. In other words, web search.
But, it it's an agentic process that it
goes through. It's a bot, okay? And you
want those bots to be able to get to
your stuff. More importantly, you want
CCBot to be able to get to your stuff
because this is Common Crawl's bot, all
right? And this is the bot that is used
a lot, not the bot itself, but the
training or the index that it gets. So,
basically what happens is every single
month CCBot scours the whole internet
and builds a whole database of basically
a snapshot of the internet, okay? It's a
huge open-source database. What happens
is OpenAI and Anthropic and all these
companies, they just download that whole
database and that becomes a piece of
their future training of their model,
okay? They don't take everything in that
download. They take that download and
they break it down and filter it down
ends up to a so much smaller core that
they'll use for the training. You need
to make sure that your website is
accessible for CCBot because it's
basically like one of the most critical
parts for your brand getting baked into
the actual model, which is like the
ultimate thing that you want. You want
to get baked into the model, but also
make sure that you're doing well in
retrieval. So, that's the best of both
worlds. It begins with CCBot. That's the
beginning part of it, okay? And then
some more advanced stuff here. You can
see that this is really based on helping
all of these things here for the agent
retrieval is all just to make it easier
for the agents to understand your
website and navigate your website and
use use website. This stuff is so easy
to do if you're using AI or Claude. You
just come in here, I just download
markdown, and Woody is a completely
agentic website. So, I just go into our
AI Here's all the stuff that we need to
fix. The AI builds out a plan, fixes all
the problems, and then it's good to go.
And I'll show you the before and after
of this process, okay? So,
before, I think this one we did not have
any of the agentic measures in place.
So, you can see here, okay? So, none of
the agent retrieval enhancements at all
on our own website, okay? Except with
markdown, which I'm still a little
skeptical to do at this point. But, all
of these agentic variables were taken
care of. Now, how do we do this? Wasn't
magical. I just downloaded the markdown,
gave it to the AI, and said, "I We need
to make our website more agent friendly,
okay?" And the AI just figured out and
built it all, and it was done in less
than an hour, okay? Every website can do
this. It requires almost no investment,
and it has a lot of upside, okay?
Because, honestly, it's a weird time
right now because doing SEO and doing AI
search optimization, a lot of it is
thinking about You want to make sure
that the website is really built well
for agents and humans equally, maybe
even a little more leaning towards the
agents because now they're about 60%,
give or take. So, this report will help
you kind of look under the hood on any
page that you're working on. So, that is
an overview of how I would formulate a
strategy for an e-commerce website with
a good brand like this, okay? And as you
can see, there's a lot of work that has
to be done, and there's a lot of
off-site work. There's a lot of on-site
work. But, this is what it takes to win
today. This is much SEO is not just SEO
anymore. It is clearly much more than
that. It's basically digital marketing.
So, if you want to succeed in AI search
optimization, search everywhere
optimization, which is how I like to
define SEO these days, you need to be
really focused on doing great digital
marketing. So, if you want to see more
videos like this, please subscribe, and
I'll see you in the next one. Thanks.